# Haiqa Sheraz Alhassan

n haiqa-sheraz-alhassan-630296204 | ♥ haiqa-sheraz | ♥ haiqa.sheraz@gmail.com | • +966535028361 | • +923362214065

## **Artificial Intelligence Developer**

Highly skilled AI developer with experience in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), Python programming, Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Chatbot development. Have knowledge of popular frameworks such as Langchain, LlamaIndex, Tensorflow and Pytorch and experience with data analysis in Tableau and PowerBI.

## **EDUCATION**

**BS Artificial Intelligence** 

Karachi

**FAST-NUCES** 

September 2020 to June 2024

A Levels Pakistan International School

Jeddah 2018 to 2020

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

General : OOP, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Computer Vision, Natural Language Process-

ing, Deep Learning, Chatbot development, Model deployment, Front-end development, Retrieval

**Augmented Generation** 

Languages : Python, C, C++, C#, HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL

: Langchain, LlamaIndex, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Streamlit, Flask, GradientAI, FastAPI **Frameworks** 

Libraries : Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Scipy, Seaborn

: MongoDB, PHPMyAdmin **Databases** 

**Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Google Colab, Microsoft Bot Framework, Microsoft Cognitive Services, Postman

#### EXPERIENCE

#### AI SOLUTIONS ENGINEER

July 2024 - December 2024

Imperium Dynamics

- Developed a bot using Microsoft Bot Framework that processes Teams meeting transcripts, generates summaries and action items, and is deployed on Azure with full integration into Microsoft Teams
- Worked on a **Products Search System** which allows users to search for information about products and usage. Input can be text, image, or voice and response is retrieved through Azure Blob Storage.
- Created a chat streaming application using GPT-4 model, with real-time text-to-speech conversion for responses powered by Microsoft Cognitive Services
- Learned to convert functions into FastAPI endpoints
- Developed a Streamlit + RAG application using Langchain, allowing users to upload PDFs or documents and ask queries related to the content.

#### **ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT IN DATA & AI (INTERNSHIP)**

October 2023 - December 2023

TheCoded

- Conducted Research on Microsoft Copilot
- Developed ML chatbot on medical applications

## **PROJECTS**

## **FYP-Skintelligent**

September 2023 - May 2024

Al Skincare Regime Generation System

 A smart solution for skincare enthusiasts who need guidance on the best products and routines for their unique skin needs

Leveraging LlamaIndex, Retrieval Augmented Generation techniques and Pytorch, Vision Transformer
assesses severity of acne and wrinkles on skin. This input, along with more features are fed to LLM (Mistral-7B)
which generates user-tailored skincare regime

#### **Product Visual Search System**

November 2023

Computer Vision + Streamlit

- · Developed a recommendation system for product and image suggestions from user inputs
- Integrated 50,000 image embeddings into Pinecone, using the CLIP model for retrieval

PDF Summarizer February 2024

Generative AI (huggingface + streamlit)

• Utilizing summarization pipeline of **Lamini-Flan T5** with 248M parameters, used to generate precise summaries of any input PDF

Medical Chatbot January 2024

LLM Finetuning (python + gradientai)

- An Al-powered interface that guides users with personalized medical advice, treatments, and precautions, just like a general physician
- Used the Nouse-Hermes Llama2 model from GradientAI, fine-tuned using a medical responses dataset from HuggingFace

## **Sentiment Analysis on Movie Reviews**

May 2023

NLP + ML

- A system to classify movie reviews as positive, negative, or neutral
- Used TF-IDF for numeric representation, achieving 82.32% accuracy with Naive Bayes and 98.35% accuracy using LSTM after just five epochs

#### **Website for NFT Marketplace**

March 2022

Databases

 Created an interactive user interface with HTML and CSS, with MySQL database structure and PHP to securely connect the frontend and backend - buying, selling, and exploring NFTs

Global Terrorism Report July 2023

Data Analysis (Tableau)

• Used visualization techniques including heatmaps, word-clouds, line graphs, and bar charts

## **CERTIFICATIONS / AWARDS**

• Dean's List (GPA: 3.81)

**FAST-NUCES** 

Runner Up in Computer Vision Competition

AI-NEXUS FAST

Tensorflow Developer Professional Certificate

DeepLearning.ai

Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Udemy

### **LEADERSHIP ROLES**

· Media and Promotions Head

**Fast Data Science Society** 

Media Content Co-Head

Procom-FAST